A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Press Office Records, 2004-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Press Office Records 2004-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
The Library of Virginia
44739
3.95 cu. ft. (13 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 44739 transferred on 14 January 2010.
Historical Information
The Press Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state government. During Governor Tim Kaine's administration, the Press Office was responsible for shaping communication strategy, communicating with the public, handling relations with the press, managing the Governor's Web site and providing advice/guidance on agency public communications. The Press Office reviewed all documents with quotes from or references to the Governor, press releases on high profile/controversial agency issues, Governor's talking points, Cabinet talking points on high profile/controversial issues and grant announcements. The Press Office created press releases and made them publicly available, gathered and analyzed newspaper and magazine articles and television coverage pertaining to Governor Kaine and his administration, and maintained a file of photographs taken and collected by the Governor's Photographer that document Governor Kaine's public appearances. The Press Office was also responsible for making the Governor's public schedule, press releases, executive orders, proclamations, and selected speeches available online.
On 11 January 2006, Governor-elect Tim Kaine named Delacey Skinner as Communications Director. The Communication Director (Skinner, January 2006-December 2008 and Lynda Tran (2009-2010) supervised the Press Office. She was assisted in her responsibilities by a Press Secretary (Kevin Hall, January 2006-October 2007 and Gordon Hickey (October 2007-January 2010), additional press staff, a webmaster and photographer. In addition, the Communications Director oversaw the work of the Constituent Services Director whose staff members responded to inquiries of the public received via mail, phone and email.
Scope and Content
The Press Office Records of Governor Timothy M. Kaine are housed in 13 archival boxes. The collection is arranged into three (3) series. Series have been designated for: I. Records of Communication Director; II. Records of the Press Secretary; and III. Multimedia Files. These records include correspondence, memorandums, talking points and photographs, digital files and videos. These records document the press office activities of the Kaine administration (2006-2010).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Records of the Communication Director, 2005-2009
II. Records of the Press Secretary, 2005-2007
III. Multimedia Files, 2004-2010
Related Material
Office of the Governor-Tim Kaine
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration Electronic Files, Email, 2002-2010 (bulk 2006-2009). This collection documents the email of the Kaine Administration (2006-2010). The Communications Office Electronic Files series documents the electronic communication of the Communication Office of the Kaine Administration. This series contains 22064 emails in twelve (12) subseries. Subseries have been designated for A. Lynda Tran Email; B. Jeff Kraus Email; C. Gordon Hickey Email; D. Maurice A. Henderson II Email; E. Jeff Tiller Email; F. Robin Winchell Email; G. Michael Kelly Email; H. Lauren Cunningham Email; I. Doug Scott Email; J. Laura DeLibero Email; K. Amanda Howe Email; and L. Michaele White Email. There are 127 privacy protected and confidential emails in this series that are restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800 and 2.2-3705.1-8. Types of restricted information may include, but are not limited to: clemency records, and records containing personal/personnel information. The PST files for Delacey Skinner, Communications Director from January 2006 to December 2008, and Kevin Hall, Press Secretary from January 2006 to November 2007, were empty. However, email messages sent by Skinner and Hall may be found in the email files of other members of the Kaine Administration (Executive Office, Policy Office, Communications Office, etc.). The Library of Virginia Email Project - Governor Tim Kaine Portal provides access to the Kaine email collection and includes guides to other Kaine administration records.
The Governor Tim Kaine Administration Web Archive Collection, 2006-2010 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Anne Holton), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Bob McDonnell and William C. Mims), two statewide officials elected in the same cycle as Governor Kaine. The governor's website contains a complete record of Kaine administration press releases.
The Timothy M. Kaine Administration (2006-2010) Cabinet Weekly Reports Digital Collection contains the weekly reports submitted to the Governor and Chief of Staff by the Governor's Cabinet, including the Secretaries of Administration (Viola Baskerville), Agriculture and Forestry (Robert S. Bloxom), Commerce and Trade (Patrick O. Gottschalk), Commonwealth (Daniel C. LeBlanc, Jan-Mar. 2006 and Katherine K. Hanley (Mar. 2006-2010), Education (Dr. Thomas R. Morris), Finance (Jody Wagner, 2006-2008 and Richard D. Brown, 2008-2010), Health and Human Resources (Marilyn Tavenner), Natural Resources (Preston Bryant), Public Safety (John W. Marshall), Technology (Aneesh Chopra, 2006-2009 and Leonard M. Pomata, 2009-2010), and Transportation (Pierce Homer). Also included are reports by the Assistant to the Governor for Commonwealth Preparedness (Robert Crouch), Office of Constituent Services (Marc Cheatham, 2006-2007 and Amber Amato, 2007-2010), Press Office, Policy Office and Virginia Liaison Office. Reports were submitted each Thursday and placed in a binder for the Governor that he took with him at the end of the day on Friday. A second copy of the report was made for the Chief of Staff. The level of detail varied for each cabinet officer and items of importance were highlighted by staff for the Governor. Each report contains information on legislation, Governor's initiatives/special projects, agency matters/operations, events/agency visits, audits/investigations/compliance, stakeholder issues and pending decisions. Governor Kaine wrote handwritten notes and/or marked-up some reports with post-it notes and requested follow up information from the person submitting the report. Those questions and answers are included in this series. This series provides a weekly account of the issues and policy decisions of the Kaine Administration.
A Guide to the Governor Timothy M. Kaine Administration YouTube Channel Videos, 2008-2010. This collection consists of 63 videos that were originally posted onto YouTube by Governor Tim Kaine's Webmaster between March 2008 and January 2010. Governor Kaine formally announced the creation of the governor's YouTube channel in a 6 May 2008 press release.
Contents List
- I. Records of the Communication Director, 2005-2009., Extent: 0.88 cubic feet (3 boxes). (Box 1-3)
  The Records of the Communication Director (Delacey Skinner, 2006-2008 and Lynda Tran, 2009-2010) are housed in three (3) boxes. The original file order has been maintained. These records consist primarily of policy background material, drafts of major speeches by Governor Kaine, Skinner's handwritten notepads, and a compilation of priority actions and policy positions taken by Kaine during his 2005 campaign. These records include correspondence, talking points, presentations, memorandum, e-mail, reports, speeches, and notes.
  Notable documents include: Proposed Communication Plan, Office of Governor Timothy M., Kaine, 2009-2010 (b1, f1); memorandum from Lynda Tran to Governor Kaine, dated 11 September 2009, outline an end-of-term communication plan (b1, f1); multiple drafts of Governor Kaine's 2006 State of the Commonwealth address (b2, f1); working outline and draft of Kaine's 2006 State of the Union Response (b2, f2); and multiple drafts of Kaine's 2008 State of the Commonwealth address (b2, f8).
  - Communication Planning, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Potential Press Events, 2008-2009 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Press Office Staff Reports, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Transportation, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Illegal Immigration, 2007-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Coal Plant (Dominion's Virginia City Hybrid Energy Center), ca. 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2008 Legislative Packages (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Uranium Mining, ca. 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Status Report: Governor's Office Web Sites and Other Projects, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Do Not Sell Registry (ED 5 Consumer Privacy Working Group), 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Health Reform Commission, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - FY 2008-2013 Six Year Improvement Program (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget Related, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campaign Promises, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Mental Health, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Film Industry, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Pre-K Outreach, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Pre-K Proposal, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Pre-K Background Material, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Speeches and Articles
    - State of the Commonwealth Address, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - State of the Union Response, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Performance Management" Draft of Op Ed by Governor Tim Kaine for Capitol Connections, Summer 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Draft of stay of execution for Christopher Emmett, June 2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Draft of "Virginia's Energy Policy" by Governor Tim Kaine, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Budget Rollout/Speech, December 2007 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Lawyer article, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notepads, 2006-2008 and undated (part one) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notepads, 2006-2008 and undated (part two) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notepads, 2006-2008 and undated (part three) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Notepads, 2006-2008 and undated (part four) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Compilation of priority action items and policy positions, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Governor-Elect Tim Kaine's 2005 Transportation Program (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Governor's Briefing Materials, Southern Governors' Association Annual Meeting, 8-11 August 2008 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- II. Records of the Press Secretary, 2005-2007., Extent: 1.63 cubic feet (5 boxes). (Box 4-8)
  The Records of the Press Secretary (Kevin Hall, January 2006-October 2007) are housed in five (5) boxes. Original order was impossible to ascertain. The records have been put in chronological order by the processing archivist. These records consist primarily of documents related to the 2006 budget/transportation plan, 2007 budget/transportation plan, and press releases. Kevin Hall also served as Governor Mark Warner's deputy press secretary and press secretary. A few records in this series date from that service. These records include correspondence, talking points, presentations, memorandum, e-mail, reports, schedules, speeches, and notes.
  Notable documents include: copy of public opinion poll by Benson Strategy Group on transportation needs and solutions, dated 29 December 2005 (b4, f1); draft and final text of Governor Kaine's response to the State of the Union, 31 January 2006 (b4, f1); memorandum from Pete Brodnitz, Benenson Strategy Group, to Governor Kaine, date 24 February 2006, on new internal polling on transportation issues (b4, f3); Transportation Communications Strategy, 4 April 2006 (b4, f3); post-budget deal talking points, 18 June 2006 (b4, f4); memorandum from Secretary of Transportation Pierce R. Homer to Governor Kaine, dated 31 January 2007, initial review of Tunnel Project [Tysons - part of Dulles Corridor Metrorail Project] (b5, f2); Governor Kaine's schedule for 3 May 2007 (Queen Elizabeth and Prince Philip visit to Richmond) (b5, f4); Governor's schedule for 23 June 2007 (meeting with Virginia Tech Families) (b5, f5); and copies of Statement of Economic Interests for Tim Kaine, 2005-2007 (b7, f8).
  - December 2005-February 2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - February 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - February 2006-April 2006 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - April 2006-June 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - June 2006-July 2006 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - August 2006-December 2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - January 2007-February 2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - February 2007-April 2007 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - May 2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - June 2007 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - June 2007-August 2007 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - August 2007 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - August 2007 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - August 2007-September 2007 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - September 2007 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - September 2007-October 2007 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - October 2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notepads, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Notepads, 2005-2006 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous material, 2005 and undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Reference Material (part one) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Reference Material (part two) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Copies of Statement of Economic Interests for Tim Kaine, 2005-2007 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Budget Materials (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - FY 2008 Agency Budget Reduction Plan, Virginia Dept. of Planning and Budget, Fall 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- III. Multimedia Files, 2004-2010., Extent: 1.44 cubic feet (5 boxes). (Box 9-13)
  The Multimedia Files are housed in five (5) boxes and is arranged by format. Formats include: DVD, audio files, digital photographs, documents on CD, video tapes (VHS and Beta) and photographic prints. Records are arranged in chronological order within each format category. These records include interviews, major speeches, public service announcements (PSAs), and photographs of Governor Tim Kaine. Some of this material dates from when Kaine was Lt. Governor. The photographic prints are not identified (event or date).
  Notable DVDs include: Fairfax Chamber of Commerce gubernatorial debate between Jerry Kilgore (R) and Tim Kaine (D), moderated by Tim Russert, 13 September 2005; CBS-6 WTVR gubernatorial debate moderated by Larry Sabato, 9 October 2005; inaugural entertainment, parade, and inaugural address, 14 January 2006; State of the Commonwealth Addresses, 16 January 2006, 10 January 2007 and 10 January 2008; Kaine's Democratic State of the Union Response, 31 January 2006; Virginia Tech Convocation, 17 April 2007; Queen Elizabeth II visit to Virginia, 3 May 2007; Attorney General Christmas Party 2007 video by David Clementson [abusive driver fees/Santa lost his license plate - includes McDonnell, Decker, Kent, Gov. Kaine]; and Governor Tim Kaine address to Electoral College, December 2008.
  Notable audio files include: Governor-Elect Tim Kaine Transportation Meeting in Roanoke, 18 November 2005 and Kaine's final Ask the Governor program on WTOP, 22 December 2009 (President Barack Obama and Governor-Elect Bob McDonnell called in).
  Notable digital photographs include: Governor Tim Kaine's inauguration in Williamsburg, 14 January 2006; Kaine's mideast trip (Afghanistan and Iraq), March 2006; and Kaine's European trade mission, 11-18 November 2006; Queen Elizabeth's visit to Virginia, 3 May 2007.
  Notable photographic prints include: Governor Tim Kaine and Anne Holton with President George W. Bush and First Lady Laura Bush, undated; Governor Kaine, Lt. Governor Bill Bolling and Attorney General Bob McDonnell with members of Virginia's Congressional Delegation (Senator John Warner, Senator James Webb, Representative Thelma Drake, Bobby Scott, Randy Forbes, Bob Goodlatte, Eric Cantor and Jim Moran, ca. 2007 or 2008?; Governor Kaine with Governors Mark Warner, George Allen, Doug Wilder, Gerald Baliles, Chuck Robb and Linwood Holton, undated; Governor Kaine with Queen Elizabeth II, May 2007; Tim Kaine for Governor rally, ca. 2005; and Governor Kaine's inauguration, 14 January 2006.
  - DVDs
    - Virginia Hispanic Chamber of Commerce (VAHCC) 2005 Gala, "Bridging Cultures, Building Communities," 4 April 2005 - 7:54 minutes (Box 9, Disc 1)
    - Landmarks of Greater Richmond, introduction by Governor Mark Warner, 6 May 2005 - 19:01 minutes (Box 9, Disc 2)
    - DVD contains multiple events/clips: (Box 9, Disc 3)
      - News Channel 8, Fairfax Chamber of Commerce Debate between Jerry Kilgore (R) and Tim Kaine (D), moderated by Tim Russert, 13 September 2005 (clips)
      - CBS-6 WTVR Richmond, Gubernatorial Debate between Jerry Kilgore (R) and Tim Kaine (D), moderated by Larry Sabato, 9 October 2005 (clips)
      - State of the Union Response, 31 January 2006 - 10:52 minutes
      - Virginia Tech Convocation, 17 April 2007 - 9:01 minutes
      - Hour of Power, 29 April 2007 - 10:26 minutes
      - Fox News Sunday, 24 February 2008 - 13:35 minutes
      - CNN with Wolf Blitzer, 18 March 2008 - 5:36 minutes
      - Civil Rights Memorial Dedication, 21 July 2008 - 6:45 minutes
      - Virginia Democratic Convention Video, August 2008 - 4:18 minutes
    - News Channel 8, Fairfax Chamber of Commerce Debate between Jerry Kilgore (R) and Tim Kaine (D), moderated by Tim Russert, 13 September 2005 - 1:00:19 hours (Box 9, Disc 4)
    - CBS-6 WTVR Richmond, Gubernatorial Debate between Jerry Kilgore (R) and Tim Kaine (D), moderated by Larry Sabato, 9 October 2005 - 57:37 minutes (Box 9, Disc 5)
    - Bradley and Gaige Television Productions, That Culpeper Feeling, Episode 235, includes interview with Governor-Elect Tim Kaine, ca. December 2005 - 2:00:30 hours (Box 9, Disc 6)
    - Virginia Farm Bureau, Down Home Virginia, Episode 49, includes interview with Governor-Elect Tim Kaine, January 2006 - 29:44 minutes (Box 9, Disc 7)
    - Pre-Inaugural Celebration, Governor-Elect Tim Kaine, Inaugural Ball in Abingdon, ARC TV, 7 January 2006 - 1 video file (48:06 minutes) (Box 9, Disc 8)
    - Inaugural Entertainment, Williamsburg, Virginia, Appalachian Regional Community (ARC) TV, 13 January 2006 - 3 video files (28:25, 34:41 and 29:00 minutes) (Box 9, Disc 9)
    - Inauguration, Williamsburg, Virginia, ARC TV, 14 January 2006 - 2 video files (20:13 and 41:29 minutes) (Box 9, Disc 10)
    - Inaugural Parade, Williamsburg, Virginia, ARC TV, 14 January 2006 - 2 video files (9:15 and 48:15 minutes) (Box 9, Disc 11)
    - Inaugural Entertainment, Richmond, Virginia, ARC TV, 14 January 2006 - 1 video file (43:25 minutes) (part I) (Box 9, Disc 12)
    - Inaugural Entertainment, Richmond, Virginia, ARC TV, 14 January 2006 - 1 video file (1:25:50 hours) (part II) (Box 9, Disc 13)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, Speech to the General Assembly, 16 January 2006 - 43 minutes (1 DVD master and 2 service copies) (Box 9, Disc 14)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, WAVY-TV clips on the VHDA Genesis Project, 22 March 2006 (Box 9, Disc 15)
    - Chesapeake Legislative Review, WCTV 48, City of Chesapeake, March 2006, includes interview with Governor Tim Kaine - 32:52 minutes (Box 9, Disc 16)
    - Campaign for Fitness, Governor Tim Kaine visits Brookland Elementary School, 4 May 2006 - 6:10 minutes (Box 9, Disc 17)
    - Telenoticias-64, Washington, DC, 6:30 News Cast, 18 May 2006, includes brief interview with Governor Tim Kaine - 23:40 minutes (Box 9, Disc 18)
    - Virginia Housing Development Authority, "Affordable Housing Fair," 18 May 2006 - 30 seconds (Box 9, Disc 19)
    - ARC TV, A New Economy Tourism Conference, 13 June 2006 - 37:08 minutes (Box 9, Disc 20)
    - Caritas Ribbon Cutting, WRIC and WTVR clips, 29 June 2006 - 30 seconds each (Box 9, Disc 21)
    - Virginia Farm Bureau, Down Home Virginia, Episode 54, June 2006 - 28:22 minutes (Box 9, Disc 22)
    - Secretary of Technology Aneesh Chopra's prerecorded remarks for the September 15 NOVA RHIO Launch Summit, 15 September 2006 - 13:24 minutes (Box 9, Disc 23)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, Northrup Gruman Gift to University of Virginia at Wise, 18 September 2006 - 49:38 minutes (Box 9, Disc 24)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, Latino/Hispanic Heritage Month, 20 September 2006, Zona Latina TV - 3:53 minutes (Box 9, Disc 25)
    - National Federation of Press Women, 2007 Conference, Richmond, Virginia, Promotional DVD [created ca. September 2006] - 3:50 minutes (Box 9, Disc 26)
    - Secretary of Technology Aneesh Chopra, Remarks to Southwest Virginia Community College ["Fast Track Program"], 18 October 2006 - 9:50 minutes (Box 9, Disc 27)
    - Virginia's Region 2000 Partnership's Strategic Plan Presentation, Guest Speaker: Governor Tim Kaine, 24 October 2006 - 42:40 minutes (Box 9, Disc 28)
    - Video tribute to J. Robert Bray, Darden Award for Regional Leadership, 2 November 2006 - 11:30 minutes (includes congratulations from Governor Kaine) (Box 9, Disc 29)
    - Virginia Dept. of Game and Inland Fisheries, Virginia Capital Trail, Opening Ceremony, 21 November 2006 - 17 minutes (Box 9, Disc 30)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, State Parks VAB PSA, Virginia Dept. of Conservation and Recreation, 29 November 2006, two 30 second PSAs (Box 9, Disc 31)
    - Perspective, Anne Holton, record date 12 December 2006 - 26:46 minutes (Box 9, Disc 32)
    - JCRB/AJC Dinner Honoring Gary Forsee Featuring Governor Tim Kaine, December 2006 - 1:22:02 hours (Box 9, Disc 33)
    - Sorensen Institute for Political Leadership at the University of Virginia, 2006 - 15 minutes (Box 9, Disc 34)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, State of the Commonwealth Address, Jamestown, Virginia, 10 January 2007 - 40:37 minutes (3 copies) (Box 9, Disc 35)
    - Democracy in Action in Rural America by Star City Studios, Laura George and Kate Irwin Speak to the Board of Corrections, 17 January 2007 - 24:36 minutes (Box 9, Disc 36)
    - Comcast Spotlight, Read Across America PSA, Governor Tim Kaine, Lane Ramsey, Lt. Governor Bill Bolling, Mike Batten and Cecil Rhu Harris, 19 March 2007, each 30 seconds (Box 9, Disc 37)
    - Governor Tim Kaine visits James Carville's Topics in American Politics Class, Northern Virginia Community College, March 2007 - 1:18:32 hours (Box 9, Disc 38)
    - Virginia Tech Convocation, 17 April 2007 - 70 minutes (Box 9, Disc 39)
    - Google/Virginia Press Conference, Library of Virginia, 30 April 2007 - 19:35 minutes (Box 9, Disc 40)
    - Queen Elizabeth II in Virginia, 3 May 2007, A Royal Welcome - 04:52:26 minutes; The Queens Visit - 54:32:16 minutes (Box 9, Disc 41)
    - Virginia's Royal Welcome, PGM Clean 2, 3 May 2007 - 1:08:43 hours (Box 9, Disc 42)
    - Virginia's Royal Welcome, PGM Clean 3, 3 May 2007 - 1:29:13 hours (Box 9, Disc 43)
    - Virginia's Royal Welcome, PGM Clean 4, 3 May 2007 - 24:12 minutes (Box 9, Disc 44)
    - Governor Tim Kaine's Address, Commencement Exercises, Southwest Virginia Community College, 10 May 2007 - 19:45 minutes (Box 9, Disc 45)
    - Southeastern Association of Tax Administrators (SEATA) 2008 Invitation, created by Virginia Dept. of Taxation (includes Governor Kaine), 19 June 2007 - 6:30 minutes (Box 9, Disc 46)
    - Colonial Downs 2007 Virginia Derby, TV CBS, includes brief statement from Governor Tim Kaine, 21 July 2007 - 58:42 minutes (Box 9, Disc 47)
    - Governor Tim Kaine, Early Childhood Development Program, Moton Elementary School, WHCS-46 Hampton City Schools, 11 September 2007 - 59:25 minutes (Box 9, Disc 48)
    - Own Your Future (Long Term Care DVD) includes brief message from Governor Tim Kaine, undated possibly ca. 2007? (Box 9, Disc 49)